good evening ladies and gentlemen a very
warm welcome to ICICI Lumar General
Insurance company limited's Q2 and H1 FY
2025 earnings conference
call from the senior management team we
have with us today Mr sanjie mantri MD
and CEO of the company Mr gopal
balachandran
CFO Mr Girish nyak Chief technology and
health underwriting and claims Mr sandep
gadia Chief corporate solutions group
and Mr Anand singi Chief retail and
government
business please note that any statements
or comments made in today's call that
may look like forward-looking statements
are based on information presently
available to the management and do not
constitute an indication of any future
performance as future involves risks and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from the current
views being expressed
as a reminder all participant lines will
be in the listen only mode there will be
an opportunity for you to ask questions
after the presentation
concludes should you need assistance
during this conference please signal the
operator by pressing star and then zero
on your Touchstone
phone I now hand the conference over to
Mr sanjie mantri MD and CEO iici lumbar
General Insurance Limited thank you and
over to you sir thank you
good evening to each one of you thank
you for joining the earning conference
call of icsl Omar General Insurance
Company Limited for quarter 2 nh1
Financial year
2025 let me give you a brief overview of
the industry Trends and developments
that we have witnessed in the uing
months post this our CFO Mr gopal
balachandran will share the financial
performance of the company for the
quarter and a half year anded September
30th
2024 during the quarter one
2025 India's real GDP grew by 6.7%
primly driven by private consumption
moving into the Q2 of financial year
2025 the government expenditure started
witnessing an uptake GST collections
Contin to remain steady and Q for Q2 and
the direct tax collections are growing
at a decent pace this may provide much
needed support to retail spending in the
upcoming festive season further a normal
Monsoon may help Drive rural demand in
coming months nevertheless the current
situation in West Asia region and a
substantial increase in crude prices
remains a major risk for the overall
economic
growth speaking of General Insurance
performance the industry delivered a
gdpi growth of 7% for H1 of financial
year 2025 over H1 of financial year
2024 impacted by quarter 2 Financial
year 2025 growth of
2% however excluding crop and mass
segments the industry registered grow
growth at 10.9% for H1 of 2025 and 6.9%
for quarter 2 Financial year
2025 now talking about the Auto industry
growth for the quarter was muted as
reported by CM private car with higher
Bas de grew at
1.8% two pillers grew at
12.6% and CV degw at
3.2% this this entails approximately 2.1
million private cars 10.2 million two
wheelers and8 million CVS being sold in
H1 of 2025 further the retail numbers as
reported by F has also seen de growth
for private car at 5.1% two wheer growth
at
4.7% and CV growth remained muted at
1.1% for quarter to financial year
2025 the health segment during the
quarter contined to deliver double digit
growth largely driven by retail business
registering growth of
17.7% the growth in the Group business
was moderated due to pring pressure and
the health business was impacted due to
relatively muted disbursement by
financial
institutions the commercial line segment
during the quarter was a mixed back with
industry growth at 2% while fire segment
degree at 10.7% on account of pricing
pressure however government spent on
infrastructure development and
acceleration in private sector
investment has spurred Positive Growth
especially in segments such as
engineering liability and Marine
the regulatory environment continues to
focus on policy holders interest while
fostering Innovation competition and
sustainable growth for the industry
thereby reinforcing the Authority's
vision of insurance for all by
2047 overall for the medium to long term
we remain positive that The General
insurance industry will continue to grow
given the favorable regulatory changes
low penetration and Rising disposable
income now speaking of the underwriting
performance of the industry the combin
ratio for the industry remain at 113.9
for quarter 1 Financial year 2025 as
against 13.5% for quarter 1 Financial
year
2024 for the motor business the industry
is combined ratio wors to
25.6% in quarter 1 Financial year
2025 from
121% in quarter 1 2024 which can be
largely attributed to the increase in
loss
ratios now let me update you on
performance of key business segments for
us the company's gdpi for quarter 2
Financial year 2025 grew by 10.4% as
compared to the industry growth of
2% excluding crop and mass sales the
company grew by 9.4% as compared to the
industry growth of
6.9% in the commercial line segment we
grew at 1.2% as against industry growth
of
2% we continue to maintain leadership
position in engineering Li ility and
Marine cargo segment however in the fire
segment we remain Vigilant in terms of
risk selection while maintaining a
market
share in motor segment during the
quarter we registered a growth of 16.1%
as against the industry growth of
6.2% the overall growth in motor segment
during the quarter was AED by growth in
Old
business we continue to maintain the
market share leadership with robust
capabilities across distribution and
writing claims servicing and actal
practices during the quarter we
sustained a balanced portfolio with a
mix of Private Car two wheeler and CV at
5 54.4% 24.6% and 21%
respectively our preferred partner
Network enabled us to survey 72.8% of
our non OEM claims in quarter 2 of 2025
up from 63.4% in quarter to of financial
year
2024 the health segment View at 12.3% %
in quarter 2 Financial year 2025 led by
retail has we registered a growth of
41.4% in quarter to 2025 as against
industry growth of 17.7% in the retail
Health segment our growth in quarter 2
was supported by a recently launched
product elevate a market share for
retail segment has now reached 3.5% in
quarter to a financial year
2025 in the group health employer
employee segment we we look we took a
cautious approach due to increased
competitive intensity cons consequently
we grew by 1% in quarter 2 Financial
year 2025 as compared to growth of 34.6%
in quarter one of financial year
2025 during the quarter our bank of
business de by 2.6% due to lower credit
disbursement growth in our key
relationship
Partners within this icsa group dis
distribution grew by
19.6% for quarter to a Financial year
2025 due to a continued strategic focus
on Branch Banking business we continue
to strengthen our digital business
during the quarter our customer facing
digital business grew by
14.7% constituting 6.3% of our overall
gdpi our investments in new customer
acquisition strategy through website led
to a growth in fresh business of motor
and health segment by 45.9% in quarter
to financial year 2025
our onetop solution for all insurance
and wellness needs the IL take care app
has surpassed 11.6 million user
downloads F date registering a premium
of 55 5 56.8 million for the
quarter as discussed in our previous
call we continue to harness synergies
through one Al one team under this one
one of our initiatives one Al One Call
Center we have Consolidated multiple
call centers into three specialized
teams fresh acquisition renewals and
servicing to drive Improvement in
operational efficiencies and the overall
customer experience additionally our
investment in CRM technology and AI
tools have further increased
productivity by high team and improved
customer service particularly in retail
health and motor
segments in conclusion we continue to
Spen a multi-product multi-distribution
strategy led by our focus on product
Innovation data analytics and digital
enhancements these initiatives coupled
with the spirit of one one team position
as well to capitalize on future
opportunities and drive profitable
growth I will now request goal to take
you through the financial numbers for
the Recently concluded quarter and half
year thanks aiv and uh good evening to
each one of you I will now give you a
brief overview of the financial
performance of the recently concluded
quarter and half year we have uploaded
the results results presentation on our
website you can access it as we walk you
through the performance numbers
gross direct premium income of the
company was at rupes 144.5 billion in H1
fi25 as against rupes 12472 billion in
H1 FY 24 a growth of
15.5% against the industry growth of 7%
excluding crop and Mass health gdpi
growth of the company was at 15% which
was higher than the industry growth of
10.9% in H1
fy2 gdpi was at R 67.2 billion in Q2
F525 as against R 6.86 billion in Q2 fi
24 a growth of
10.4% this again was higher than the
industry growth of 2% excluding crop and
mass sales gdpi growth of the company
was at
99.4% which was higher than the industry
growth of 6.9% in quarter to fi25 our
gdpi growth during the quarter was
mainly driven by preferred lines of
businesses on the retail side of the
business gdpi of the motor segment was
at rupes 24.8 to billion in Q2
f25 as against rup 2.38 billion in Q2 fi
24 registering a growth of
16.1% the advanced premium number was R
35.13 billion as at September 30 2024 as
against R 34.56 billion as at June 30
2024 gdpi of the health segment was Ates
15.29 billion in Q2 fi25 as against R
13.625 f524 again registering a growth
of 12.3% % our agents which includes the
point of sale distribution count was
13368 as on September 30 2024 up from
13121 as at June 30 2024 the overall
gdpa of our commercial line segment grew
by 1.2% at rupes
14.93% multiple catastrophic events
namely floods in and Andra telingana
North India Gujarat etc etc impacting
our combined isues which was 103.2 for
H1 fi25 as against 13.8% for H1
f524 excluding this impact of cat losses
which was rupees 94 billion in H1 fy2
and r83 billion in H1 FY 24
the combined ratios were
102.2 and 10 2.7% respectively combined
ratio was 10 14.5% in Q2 fi25 as against
103.9 in Q2 fi 24 again excluding the
impact of cat losses primarily we had
the cat losses in Q2 this year which was
again rupes .94 billion and rupes 48
billion in Q2 fi 24 the combined ratio
was 102.6 and 10 12.8% respectively
our investment assets during the quarter
Rose to rupes 55.57 billion as at
September 30 2024 up from rupe 51.4
billion as at June 30
2024 our investment leverage net of
borrowings was 3.91 times as at
September 30 2024 as againsted 4.14
times as at June 30
2024 investment income was at r
22.52% H1
f524 on a quarterly basis investment
income was at R 11.24 billion in Q2 F525
as against R 9.56 billion in Q2
f524 our capital gains net of impairment
on investment assets stood at rupes 5.21
billion in H1 fi25 as against R 2.82
billion in H1 f24 capital gains net of
impairment investment assets for the
quarter to fi25 stood at rupes 2.37
billion as compared to rupes 1.6 billion
in Q2 f524 our profit before tax grew by
31.9% at R 16.93 billion in H1 fi25 as
against R 12.84 billion in H1 f524
whereas PBT grew by 20.3% at rupes 9.19
billion in Q2 F525 as against rupes 7.64
billion in Q2 f524 consequently profit
after tax grew by 31.7% at r
12.74% 9.68 billion in h
fi4 profit after tax again grew by 20.2%
for this quarter to fi25 at 6.94 billion
rupees up from rupees 5.77 billion in Q2
fi4 return on average Equity was 20.3%
in H1 fi25 as against 18% in H1 f24 the
return on average equity for Q2 fi25 was
21.8% as against 21.1% in Q2 fi4
solvency ratio was healthy at 2.65 times
as at September 30 2024 as againsted
2.56 times as at June 30 2024 continued
to be higher than the minimum regulatory
requirement of 1.5 times the board of
directors of the company has declared an
interim dividend of rupes 5.5 per share
for H1 fi25 as against rupees 5 per
share which was for H1
f524 as I conclude I would like to
reaffirm that we continue to stay
focused on driving sustainable value
creation and profitable growth while
protecting the interest of policy
holders at all times I would like to
thank you all for attending this
earnings call and we will now be happy
to take any questions that you have
thank
you thank you very much we will now
begin the question and answer session
anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and one on their touchdown
telephone if you wish to withdraw
yourself from the question Q you may
press star and two participants are
requested to please use hands while
asking a question ladies and gentlemen
we will wait for a moment while the
question Q
assembles the first question is from the
line of shria Shivani from clsa please
go ahead uh thank you for the
opportunity uh I have two two questions
uh first is on the net commission rate
for the quarter it seems like it's
slightly elevated when I compare it to
the second quarter of last year could it
be uh because of uh higher sales in the
retail Health segment are we have we
changed our commission structure in that
product or is it just because the
product mix has shifted more towards
that place uh that segment uh that's the
first question and second uh sir uh
majority of the rise uh in the in
combined ratio in this quarter has been
because of the catastrophic losses uh so
will we still hold on to our guidance of
being able to touch 101.5 the as a
closing combined ratio in 4 q25 uh given
that majority from catastrophe and in
case we don't see any more Surge Cycling
so uh just the guidance around that
thank you yeah I think gopal will answer
the first one and then I'll talk about
the guidance part yeah so sh I think uh
you're absolutely right I think uh so
far as a net commission ratio numbers
are concerned it's obviously a function
of uh the mix of business that you
underwrite and uh as you would have seen
I think our approach to writing risk as
what we put out also as a part of the
opening transcript was to drive
profitable growth and therefore in that
context when you look at the mix of
business largely what we have been able
to drive is uh profitable businesses in
motor and uh the retail Health segment
in specific and relative to that I think
our growth in let's say the group health
SL commercial lines have been relatively
uh muted and that's clearly a factor
that has contributed to let's say the
change in the net commission ratio and
given the fact that we have also been a
bit cautious on the commercial line
there is also some bit of impact in so
far as uh reinsurance commissions are
concerned so because the ratio is on a
net commission basis so therefore it is
a factor of both change in business mix
as well as let's say our approach to
being a bit cautious on the commercial
line sign commercial line side which is
what has contributed to the net
commission numbers to your point on have
we changed anything in so far as U
commission structures are concerned I
think the short answer is uh I think we
keep looking for Market opportunities in
terms of how we want to ride businesses
but at an aggregate level I think what
we stand committed is to kind of make
sure that from an expense of management
standpoint which includes both
commission plus operating expenses both
of that put together as a company we
stand committed to make sure that we
well within the limit of 30% at an
aggregate level sanj so overall you're
right the Cat event uh in the quarter 2
has impacted the loss Rao by 1.9% and
thereabouts uh otherwise overall the
command issue of the company if n of C
event it looked at that's shown an
improvement uh uh in terms of the
guidance at things stand uh we have no
reason to change the guidance at this
point of time uh we very keenly will
look at the industry numbers also as
they come out on the quarter 2 and the
H1 pnl uh I spoke about uh in my own uh
script which I said that the quarter one
number for the industry has come out uh
relatively status quo while we used to
have a YY Improvement uh uh last year
and that also has come on account of
elevated loss ratio and little bit of
impact on the account of uh expenses uh
we stay committed we have no reason to
at this point of time deviate from it uh
we do look at the intensity and the
landscape that you see in the commentary
overall as to what's happening on the
commercial line of business uh we grew
ghi business at almost 31% and
thereabouts uh we and the quarter two
again you look at the numbers we have
gone down and we clearly do understand
that uh uh these are all changes the
fire business has uh had gone through a
bit of a concern in terms of where the
discounting has uh increased again
uh We've abstained from any wild
participation and still we've been able
to maintain the market share on on each
of these uh business lines so yes we
stay committed to that but we continue
to watch the market scenario I think the
just to only add to that sh I think what
we would say is uh in fact uh we will
start seeing this impact felt from an
overall Market as well um and if you
would have seen in general given our
ability to risk select portfolios our
exposure from some of these cat events
have been relatively lower compared to
the Natural market share that we have
had as a company and hence a large part
of this change consequent to the cat
losses will also be reflected from a
market perspective at the time of the
reinsurance renewals that will start
happening from the next year so in fact
the real impact is something that you
will start seeing from an industry
standpoint at the time of the
reinsurance renewals which will kick in
for next
year got it understood so you're saying
your reinsure your
catastrophe reinsurance will be priced
uh worth off for us for the industry
going ahead right because of the number
these are events that are playing out
right so honestly if you ask us could
could we have anticipated let's say
about four events coming and eating us
at an industry level in one quarter the
short answer is no and therefore and
with let's say wavering weather patterns
that you're seeing uh across periods
honestly I think one will have to kind
of wait and see how this develops and
then maybe as things move forward we
will be able to start giving you better
ins yeah
got it very useful thank you so much and
all the best thank you thank you ladies
and gentlemen we request you to please
restrict your questions to two questions
per participant you may rejoin the queue
for follow-up
questions we have the next question from
the line of PR Jen from moal oswal
please go
ahead yeah hi good evening everyone uh
just a good questions on the motor
segment so in our last quarter you had
mentioned about the grow grow in new
versus old so it would be great if you
could share a similar trajectory for H1
and just an extension to that whether
you know the the growth in the the
renewal or older business now the new
vehicle has been stronger what are the
drivers for the same that you have been
kind of been able to get more more
growth there and second question would
be on the motor Outlook again you
mentioned in the opening remarks that
the growth has been slowing down in
terms of number of
vehicles and so do you see and whatever
the Outlook that we hearing is that it
Outlook is also going to be muted in the
second half even for f season the demand
Outlook is not expected to be great so
what kind of growth trajectory should we
anticipate for the motor segment
especially in the H2 yeah those would be
my
questions PR the first one I think uh uh
if you recollect what we had said in
quarter 1 when the aggregate growth in
motor for us was about 26% at that point
of time we had said the growth in new
was about 16 and the growth in renewal
was roughly about
33% U and given what we had talked about
as a part of this opening transcript in
terms of as you rightly indicated new
being relatively muted uh pretty much on
similar lines I think if you ask us for
Quarter Two the growth in new has been
flattish uh and a large part of the
growth of that 16% that we spoke about
has been significantly aided by growth
in the renewal book or let's say the old
book which has grown at almost about 26%
uh so that's a split this is
specifically in the context of quarter 2
uh Vis what we had seen in uh q1 U to
your point on what's driving let's say
some of this uh growth I think uh as a
company I think we have always been kind
of looking at uh which we have spoken
about even in earlier calls I think
while we stay invested in obviously
leveraging our relative strength on u o
SL dealership Partnerships but at the
same time we have also been
significantly investing on our agency SL
other distributions as well and um in
that context our our strength on
distribution service use of Technology
all of that is what is kind of
significantly aiding the growth in the
renewal book plus equally if you
recollect what we also talked about uh
was also to kind of significantly move
into let's say a one one call center ini
itive under which we would we had wanted
to kind of which is also what we put out
as a part of the opening transcript to
kind of also have a significant Focus as
one of the streams in so far as
retentions are concerned and that is
also in uh in a big way is aiding the
growth in the uh old
book so on the second point on the motor
Outlook you're right uh the the overall
numbers that have come out uh for the
industry has been muted and there's
nothing new that we are talking about it
it's all over every possible you know uh
Channel as to where the industry is uh
but I was also highlight one fact that
on private car in particular which
contribut more than 50% of our uh
practice as far as motor is concerned uh
it's on a very high base we've had a
very secular run on private car as an
industry uh almost you know when the
covid was still there and then it kind
of continued for a while so on a very
high B if it is flattish also it does
not overly concerns us uh yes and two
wheer has shown better numbers but two
wheer also had recovered only 8 85% of
preo levels while private car has moved
in the zone of 130 to 140% of what it
was pre-o Peak uh commercial vehicle
mixed back but uh which can be a proxy
in many ways to the industrial activity
uh which takes place we do believe it
can pick up in quarter end of quarter 3
or maybe you know by quarter 4 uh so
overall yes we are expecting a single
digit growth uh in H2 but that itself
should suffice and this also is a
backdrop that uh as an industry we've
had not much of a TP hike uh for almost
uh you know last 3 years if I may say so
it's a it's a combined Factor uh which
stays but we stay committed to harness
what works for us so there is uh we we
are excited with two also and the
festive season has just got started food
Falls have been high uh the sales
numbers are still building up probably
we'll have a much better sense how the
festive season goes by uh by November
mid and thereabout once the Diwali part
is
over just a clarification on this uh you
mentioned the single digit growth that
you expect in next two is for vehical
sales or is it for the premium growth of
the motor segment for General Insurance
IND I'm I'm I'm talking about the
premium the vehicle sale is what I'm
referring to vehicle sale okay yeah yeah
yeah yeah yeah yeah all right thank you
s thank you thank
you the next question is from the line
of mukar ladha from Nama wealth
management limited please go ahead hi uh
good evening sir uh so so um first I
think in your opening remarks you
mentioned that on the motor segment
industry combined uh ratios have
worsened now
um in this backdrop I think H1 your
performance has been very good and um
and you know do you think that this will
be
sustainable
um given you know industry loss ratios
are worsen and so uh how how do you
think uh you know this can uh pan out do
you think
um um it the comparative intensity is is
good higher or uh yeah so that's that's
question number
one
hello you want to put your second
question if you have I should answer
this no and second sir uh you know last
year uh we were sort of discussing that
uh I a lot of your competition is sort
of above the 30% uh um you know expense
and commission ratio so and is not in
compliance of the um Norms so is IID
looking to do something about it what is
the thought process of there uh because
um you know that may help in getting
industry combined ratios under check and
and we can benefit in that scenario yeah
so so fair I think so I'll uh answer
both of them uh on the core side when
you spoke about Motors the core for the
industry has moved from 121 to
125.638 gone to
87.6 and there's an increase on the
expense set also which has taken it from
36.5 to 38% uh interesting play when you
split this in PSU and private sector
clearly psus has wor from 134 to
141 uh driven by again significant
increase in loss ratio private from 107
to 115 so that has been the kind of a
movement that you have seen in loss
ratio uh for PSU for private sector in
particular it also in a way answers as
to what Lombard can look at it has
remained in the zone of 74.2 to 75% so
it's and there's a marginal increase in
the private sector as far as expense
ratio is concerned where it's moved from
41.1% to
43.5 uh so from the balance perspective
and where I Journey can be while I don't
want to stretch the line too far we stay
committed and we do back ourselves on
two count uh one is uh in terms of the
selection that we are able to do as an
entity and secondly the manner in which
we are able to service our customer
which is at speed and in a far more
efficient manner so all of that in
Combined uh we would love to you know
probably put this across that we stay
committed to where we are uh yes at an
industry level finally we are part of
our uh overall uh you know operations of
the business uh as things stand uh we
would love to see Improvement at the
industry level also because if that
happens it can create further Niche for
us and improve our combined ratio so
that's my you know uh uh take and we
stay committed to you know take care of
our motor practice we would be agile
enough to make movements between Private
Car two wheeler and commercial vehicle
as it warrants at that in a dynamic
manner at any point of time uh on the
second question in terms of the stuff
that we mentioned on expense of
management yes the data is out it's
there with the regulator uh we are in no
position to put a commment we continue
to pursue with them as to what
strictures they will do at some point of
time uh they multiple nodes and there's
lot of proactive work being done by the
regulator multiple counts including the
master circular which has come uh for
each of the product categories so we do
believe something is in the offing but
uh uh we are in position to comment as
to when and how this would get
transpired right but you definitely
expect some action to bring the industry
in line see I from from our position we
definitely will expect but we are not
the right uh uh you know set of you know
people to comment as to how and when
they will do it that prerogative fairly
and squarely stays with them but yes we
do expect that uh some uh action will be
taken by them at some point of time so
and one more question finally on the
health segment Health segment loss
ratios have sort of ver versen in the
first half and Q2 I I know seasonally is
a little bit of a weaker quarter in that
respect but is there any uh you know
structural problem in the industry you
know uh is pricing adequate what is your
sense so
uh we continue to monitor this closely
structural problem my answer is no are
there challenges which comes on account
of some bit of seasonality which leads
to increase in frequency answer is yes
there is an element of that maduka that
does uh come in uh nevertheless uh the
way the process works and the way the
regulator has created environment if
there are challenges each one of us is
well within the rights to you know seek
a reprising of the portfolio uh so
uh in an agile mode all this can be
addressed over a period of
time got it sir thank you and all the
best thank you m all the best thank you
thank
you we have the next question from the
line of sanket godha from avenders spark
please go
ahead uh yeah thank you for the
opportunity um gopal can you split the
motor growth uh for for the quarter and
for the half into new and uh old and and
in this old can you give a bit of color
that this old is driven by the existing
customers that is they are renewing uh
what they bought last year with you or
is it the business which is coming from
other companies because because compared
to the industry we we seems to be gain
significant share of Market um in this
business so so if you can give a color
bit there and how sustainable it is it
will be useful du to understand the
future outlook too and the second
question related to that is that if you
are doing more old in od then ideally
the loss ratio should doriate in od but
what but we are seeing an improvement in
one H or one quarter compared to the
last year so so just wanted to
understand what is playing in our favor
to to see that better loss istio in
motor and and lastly on on PP I believe
you you guys said last time that losses
of 65 to 70 is the number what you need
to watch out for that's the guidance you
have given um and and that was last year
and now now it is start below 65 for
first half uh just just wondering given
there is no TP price hike whether
whether you believe this number is uh
still sustainable because I'm asking
this question from the perspective that
in last three years L triangles that is
2322 21 you did not choose to take any
reserve release uh from from from motp
so so so just just wondering whether
whether this number is sustainable or
not and lastly if you can give a data
point Health loss ratio broken down into
retail and group that's it all right
perfect superb uh thanks anit uh so one
uh I think I'll take it in the in the
sequence which is the I'll start with
last and go to the first uh so all the
breakup of the heal R show which is
something that you obviously ask us
every quarter uh so hence to that extent
and uh Quarter Two of last year uh on
the employer employee side that number
was 102% Vis that quarter two of this
year that number is about 98 uh on the
retail Indemnity again quarter two
numbers are roughly about 66.6% and uh
quter two of this year is about
70.3 uh but again at the point that we
have always maintained is uh I think if
you look at on the employer employee
side largely we have said I think the
portfolio should possibly end the year
in that range of about 94 95% this is
I'm referring to the corporate health
and on the retail side I think broadly
we have talked about trying to run the
portfolio at a loss ratio around that
70% threshold so that's why we are kind
of largely working towards at least in
so far as the portfolio buildup is
concerned uh and to your third question
on the TP uh loss ratio range that we
spoke about I think one I talked about
at an aggregate motor segment level we
had said broadly the range that we are
comfortable operating at is between 65
to
67% and within that we had said OD
possibly are looking at running between
60 to 65 and third party as you rightly
mentioned was between the range of 65 to
70 uh what we also keep saying is uh
honestly I think you should keep kind of
keep looking at numbers more on ideally
multiple annual Cycles because these are
third party books which typically runs
over multiple uh long-term periods in
terms of development and and to that
extent I think at this point of time I
think we kind of uh St stay within that
range of what we spoke about which is
motor at an aggregate level of 65 to 67
and within that third party we believe
should broadly kind of run at a range of
about 65 to 70 and and and that that
also kind of resonates with one of the
other points that you rightly mentioned
which is what we are also seeing is
obviously no TP price increases and
therefore to that extent that's another
factor that we will be be mindful of in
terms of how we kind of reselect uh the
portfolios uh so that's in response to
question three to your point on question
two on the OD loss ratios I think I kind
of largely answered as a part of
question three which is I think the
range that you see even on a half yearly
basis or even within that uh if you look
at on Quarter Two broadly that loss
ratio range on own damage has been
running between uh in that range of
about 60 to 65 but uh having said that I
think uh one of the things that we have
been speaking about even in our earlier
earnings call is I think there is a lot
of thrust and focus on us to make sure
that we are able to
significantly leverage on the service
parameters uh particularly on trying to
see how we can manage the overall cost
of claims in the context of motor
specifically and if you remember one of
the initiatives that we spoke about
driving in that front was to leverage on
our PPN network uh and there again if
you would have seen uh what we have
tried to do is to the proportion of
claims that has got settled through the
PPN Network that numbers have kind of uh
clearly seen and uh increase so all in
all I think uh uh pretty much
comfortable with the range at which we
are operating at in the context of own
damage uh to your point on the second
one and to your first point I did kind
of give out the numbers of the growth
between new and old just to rate quarter
1 new grew at about 16% old book had
grown at about 33% Quarter Two as I said
the growth in new has been largely
flattish and the growth in the renewal
book has been about 26% on a half yearly
basis the growth in new has roughly been
about 7 to 8% and the growth in the
renewal book has been close to about 30%
uh 29 30% uh so that's been the the
breakup now in terms of where is that
growth largely coming in on the old side
I think as I said there is a significant
thrust on us in terms of making sure
that we we are able to retain as many
customers of ours uh and in so far as
the initiative that I kind of also spoke
about but equally what we have also been
able to see is to also get some expanded
Market as well which is why if you see
for example on motor as a category where
we used to kind of possibly uh actually
kind of see us running at a market share
of slightly less than in fact 10% uh
right now we are at a market share of
close to about 11% uh so hence in that
sense um that's also kind of aiding so
obviously we have also been accreting uh
some of the businesses from uh Market as
well so it's been a combination of both
but as I said the Endeavor is should try
and see how we can maximize retention uh
particularly at times when you see
possibly some kind of slowdown from a
market perspective then we will
obviously as I said leverage our
strengths on uh distribution service and
Technology to increase customer
retention got just follow can you give a
trend last year one is how was our
retentions and what is today in motor
just just to give a color whether it is
driv by our own book so on an average I
think what I would kind of say uh sanet
is I think if you look at it from a from
a from a motor standpoint in general and
I'm largely just confining to private
car and two wheer as categories uh on an
average I would say we would have seen
an increase in retentions ranging
between 2 to 4% uh that's the kind of uh
increase in retentions that one has seen
and the same trend line while you're
talking in the context of motor just to
kind of possibly expect a follow on on
the health side as well uh I think even
there I think what we have seen is uh
obviously a slight uptick in so far as
as our retention numbers are concerned
around pretty much around the similar
ranges so I think as a as a company we
believe there's a lot that we can do in
so far as uh retaining the customers are
concerned and and to that extent is
where we are driving a lot of our
initiatives
around got to go thanks thanks for the
answer thanks
an thank you the next question is from
the line of Aditi josi from JP Morgan
please go
ahead yeah uh thank you for taking my
question and good evening uh just
question we can speak a little louder
that would be great thank you so
much yes sorry uh is it better just two
questions uh from my side uh firstly on
the investment Level side um see that
the first half investment level was
slightly downward uh so can you please
help explain like the reason behind that
and going forward what do you think of
investment leverage Trend and uh
secondly um on the uh uh retention side
premium retention it's it was slightly
On The Higher Side um so I just want to
understand your strategy uh going
forward will you plan to rain more on
your books or how are you thinking about
it yeah that's all thank you again I
will go in the in the reverse sequence
uh so uh so if you look at the premium
retention as I said it's largely a
function of the change in the business
mix uh as I kind of outlined at the
beginning I think in quarter 2
relatively our sourcing on the
commercial lines have been uh relatively
muted where we kind of typically have
slightly higher than extent higher
higher reinsurance extent and therefore
to that extent retur are lower and given
that we were cautious that book book has
grown at a relatively slower Pace
compared to that I think we have seen a
significant uptake on both the retail
lines which is both retail Health as
well as uh our Motor Lines of businesses
both of which predominantly we end up
retaining pretty much everything on the
net account so hence to that extent is
where you would have you would have
possibly seen a slight uptick uh in so
far as the premium retentions are
concerned to your point on what can we
expect going ahead I think purely very
difficult to comment on a number because
it all depends on how we see the
momentum play out in terms of business
different lines of businesses but if you
ask us is there any change in the
thought process in terms of uh retention
versus reinsurance at this point of time
obviously there is no change in stance
but obviously we will take it as we play
through once the
discussions for the reinsurance programs
happen at the beginning of quarter 4 uh
of maybe the next calendar year
beginning so that is where we are on
premium retention to your point on
investment leverage um I think uh which
is again something that we put out as a
part of the opening transcript in the in
the context of the market being a little
slow particularly in quarter 2 uh if
You' have seen as I said industry grew
at about 13% we grew at 20 in q1 uh Vis
that market grew at about 2% at there
about in quarter 2 we grew at roughly at
about 10% So to that extent the fact
that there has been a relative slowdown
in growth that obviously kind of acts as
a factor u in so far as uh let's say the
uh investment Leverage is concerned and
secondly in general if you would have
seen the trend line uh Q2 over q1 uh
generally the the investment leverage
seems to show a declining Trend and this
trend starts to reverse as we kind of
head into the festive season or maybe
quarter three where where you will see
start seeing a lot more collections kind
of play through and hence I think to
that extent is where we are uh on a I
would say on a on a normal trajectory I
think broadly what we should say is I
think we have talked about trying to
maintain a investment average around
four times I think that's broadly the
trend line that one should expect but in
a particular quarter you can always see
some of these aberration play out and
over also one more thing just to add is
mathematically speaking if your growth
of your if your growth of profit is
higher than the growth of investment
there can be a bit of a denominator that
will come out uh it should get moderated
with cash flows over
time sure got it thank you so much thank
you thank you the next question comes
from the line of nides from investtech
please go ahead uh thanks for the
opportunity uh so my question is on
motor TP in motp last three years there
is no price hike uh and uh uh uh because
of which the loss ratio in the segment
should IDE be going up and some of the
companies I think also are going slow in
the motor TP so what is giving us
confidence that the business that we are
under think is of appropriate quality in
terms of
profitability so NES uh yes there's been
no hike and I spoke about that just some
time back uh uh the configuration in
terms of how a book is placed uh the
contribution of commercial vehicle is
around 21 or you know and we always said
will remain in that range of 18 19 to 23
24% is what we expect the commercial
vehicle is which is the bare minimum we
are more driven by private car and uh
two wheeler uh so there is a mix and
selection that comes into play uh
clearly yes industry would love to see
in certain categories uh uh increase on
the third party premium and we continue
to be in discussion with the regulator
and all the other authorities who are
involved in that uh but we stay
committed to our process of selection
and the rigor uh that which we go
through even in times when industry was
doing extremely well in certain
categories we had let go uh and had
shown a declining Trend so we have stuck
to our course and we every reason to
believe that uh we should be able to
play Play It Out The Way We have been
giving our numbers that's all I can say
at this point of
time simp the 60% combin loss ratio that
we are showing on motor TP
is it a function of uh decline
in decline in accident incidents or so
this number looks pretty good so why
that is how we are able to deliver this
number is it our underwriting or it is
the structural decline in uh decline in
incidents of the accidents or it is the
benefit of motor motor vehicle act that
we are getting now so the last so again
NES I I think we have kind kind of rated
this even in our quarter one earnings
call uh particularly on the last piece
in terms of Are We factoring in any
element of maybe a benefit in the
context of the likely implementation of
the six-month rule the short answer is
no uh so at this point of time we are
not necessarily factoring in anything in
the context of reserving uh at least so
far as the law of limitation is
concerned uh but if you ask us um I
think so far as third party is concerned
as I keep saying uh you should ideally
start looking at this number over longer
Cycles because of the development of the
inherent nature of the business in terms
of how the loss development takes place
and that's the reason why we said uh
generally at an aggregate level the
range that we are comfortable operating
at is between that 65 to 70% kind of a
threshold and even the point that sanjie
made in terms of our mix of business
there if you would have seen I think uh
a large part of our third party is
significantly kind of also contributed
by the relatively higher mix that we
have on private car and two wheelers
relative to let's say the exposures that
one has in so far as the commercial
vehicle segment is concerned so hence uh
that's also a factor that plays out and
in general I think what we have also
been able to do not just now over
periods uh I think we have been able to
significantly work on making sure that
we are able to identify Pockets which we
believe are viable from an underwriting
standpoint uh and and to that extent
that aids in Risk selection and if you
also remember even within C while I said
we have been underweight I think the
call that we took if you remember almost
about four five years back is to stay
invested in the segment where we think
there is an opportunity we would
possibly take those calls in possibly
ear marking some capital on doing the
right R selection and in hindsight I
think we have actually seen some of
these calls play out to our advantage so
all in all I think multiple factors that
is aiding but as I keep saying we just
want to reiterate I think the range that
we are comfortable operating is between
a 65 to
70% sure and this last question on two
wheer in two wheeler the sector growth
has been reasonably strong but our share
of two wheer business on a YY basis in
H1 has declined from 2% 25% so what
happening
there so that's primar the mix NES I
think again as we keep saying uh it's
all a function of how you see the uh see
the uh Market play out um and and
obviously uh I think as things as as
let's say for example Q3 typically the
cycle could again undergo a change uh
once you see some of the demands kind of
picking up so automatically you will see
the mix of business within motor
undergoing a change uh so all in all for
us there is no specific uh there's no
specific change in thought processes
unless no no I'll just add this so the
decline of 28 to 25 which were referring
to nides is more the configuration uh we
haven't lost Market sh two wheer but we
we have gained more in private car at a
faster clip so that changes the
percentage distribution uh of business
otherwise motor overall if you look at
it and which is a bigger number to see
we've moved from a 9.8 kind of a market
share to almost 11 which is 10.9% so
there's an overall gain and in that
Journey as the whichever way the
configuration comes out it more driven
by output of uh percentages of portfolio
distribution not that you've lost
anything in two wheer
sure very helpful thank you thank
you thank you the next question is from
the line of jant K from Jeff please go
ahead uh thank you for the opportunity
uh just a bit on the renewal book uh can
you help us understand how the renewal
rates across uh the segments within
motor have been trending and and how how
much has improved over the last say one
or two years uh and and maybe even the
last two quarters is that contributing
uh the renewal
growth so jant I think already kind of
possibly answered that uh I don't think
we talking specifically in the context
of uh specific Subs segments within
motor I think all that we can talk about
is to say that at an aggregate level
motor as a category we have seen an
improvement in retention broadly kind of
increasing between two 2 to 4% and
that's what I kind of also refer to
helping us relatively grow our grow our
proportion of the old business the
breakup of which I had given in response
to one of the questions and do you
expect this to continue improving from
here I mean Bas is the efforts that you
guys are taking on on improving the
renewals the short answer is yes jant
because I think one of the other points
that I spoke about is our increased
thrust that we are putting on customer
service and if you see one of the other
things that we keep talking a lot about
which is also there in our annual report
and even in multiple of our uh of our
disclosures that we have made is clearly
at least so far as customer satisfaction
score SL NPS scores are concerned it is
only seeing an uptick and that
automatically kind of in some sense AIDS
customers to kind of stay hooked uh at
least in so far as retentions are
concerned so hence to that extent that's
definitely a factor and the fact that we
are also able to divert maybe a lot of
our customers in so far as the preferred
provider network is concerned where
again so far as the customer is
concerned they are assured of uh clearly
two things one one obviously it helps in
so far as managing the overall average
cost of claims but two and more
importantly what we're able to kind of
assure the customer there is the quality
of repair and let's say the relative
turnaround time that we are able to
exhibit um in so far as uh servicing
those uh claims are concerned so that is
exactly what a customer looks for when
he or she gets a claim I think the
earliest possible time within which a
vehicle can be repaired and given back
that possibly kind of results into a
delightful experience and there we have
seen a significant uptake on the PPN
Network which again is kind of
translating into an improved retention
for
us thank you just sort of one last
followup on this uh in terms of channels
uh is some channel uh sort of helping
over others in terms of improving the
retention rates over
here Channel wise there is uh I think
again jent
uh Channel wise uh see when it comes to
retaining our own customers we have our
own direct reach out to them uh to some
extent uh it's Channel agnostic uh but
yes certain categories may end up having
better retention then uh other Channel
website has a good retention agency
business has a much better retention uh
OEM relatively at times get distributed
may have a lower one but when we
approach our customers through call
center in terms of retaining it uh uh
it's more a process Improvement and a
consistent reach out that we have
created which is helping us retain
is digital slightly better over over
agency over here historically it's been
better there's no there's no doubt on
that
yes thank you very much and
congratulations on a great set of
numbers thank you thanks J thank you so
much thank you we have the next question
from the line of prish upal from ilara
Securities please go
ahead yeah hi thanks so for taking my
question um just wanted to understand
the context of the rising C cat losses
so you know some color in terms of how
the pricing is on the reinsurance side
specifically on the you know the cat
events how do you see that mean possibly
moving the next year or uh in the medium
term uh and um in case there is some
kind of reinsurance price hike what
strategy do you think would be viable in
terms of you know at an industry level
the pass passing on of the cost or the
absorption and second I wanted to
understand in the health segment uh you
know what is the mix between the old and
the new book and if possibly you could
give some color on the loss ratio split
between the renewal book and the new
book uh so I think on the on the first
one um in so far as writing Rising cat
losses are concerned I think your point
is absolutely right and that is exactly
what we kind of uh keep looking for now
again if I were slightly go back to
history uh if you remember almost about
four five years back when the market had
seen stress particularly in fire line of
business at that point of time clearly
reinsurers had stepped in and they had
said in case if companies wants to Avail
appropriate reinsurance capacity the
market has to be more disciplined in so
far as pricing is concerned and to that
extent is where they had kind of
calibrated pricing terms and the extent
of possibly reinsurance commissions that
they would be kind of ascribing to
individual companies and in that context
if You' have seen from an icsl Lombard
standpoint given that we were largely
exhibiting a profitable book in terms of
our ability to reselect better quality
book we were actually able to keep
improving our panel of reinsurers and
relatively our terms on reinsurance were
also better uh now uh and therefore now
when you look at in that context if the
market further improved pricing that is
very very positive uh because that in
some sense AIDS Market to get far more
disciplined because if reur where to
kind of Define an increase in price then
that's a call that companies will have
to take in terms of their ability to
pass on to let's say what they're able
to do in so far as keeping it on the net
so any increase in pricing but all this
will start getting reflected once we do
our reinsurance uh conversations which
will happen towards quarter four of this
year so we will see how that plays out
uh to your point on uh on the health
side I think uh for us the growth I
think is aided by uh both contribution
by as as I said even on the motor while
I spoke about on retention even at that
point of time I had said even on health
there is a significant Focus for us and
therefore to that extent we have also
seen an improvement in the retention
ratios of customers on health as well
and in so far as the uh growth numbers I
think it is a growth that is aided by
both retention of customers and more
importantly also if you see I think the
newly launched solution Elevate
particularly that we launched in quarter
2 of this year that has been received
very very well across multiple
stakeholders and that's why when you
look at retail Health as a category the
market share which was largely hovering
around 2.9% or thereabout for Quarter
Two that number stands at about 3.5%
while it's an outcome of just one
quarter as we launched this solution but
obviously I think we are quite excited
and happy with the way how this has
played out and honestly we will have to
kind of keep this momentum going as we
kind of look forward um to your point on
what could be the split in so far as the
loss ratio of new and the renewal book
is concerned honestly to my mind I think
that's purely a function of what kind of
a mix of business that we write um and
our our objective will be obviously
right a combination of both new and
renewal and that's why I kind of talked
about in the context of the overall loss
ratio that we are comfortable on the
retail Health side which is roughly at
around 70% the mix thereon is the split
between new and renewal will be purely a
function of what mix of thises that we
write okay uh so just one followup uh
you know in terms of uh uh the industry
loss ratios that we seeing across the
board have been rising so is that driven
more by frequency of claims or is it
also from I mean or is it just purely
claim size that has been increased uh
such frequency numbers at the industry
levels are not available so very
difficult to commend but if the loss
ratio is the one which is contributing
more it can be a contribution of nothing
but frequency and the average claim size
that comes into play is uh what our
understanding is yeah okay yeah thank
you okay thank
you thank you ladies and gentlemen we
will take that as a last question for
today I would now like to hand the
conference over to Mr sanjie mantri for
closing comments over to you sir yeah
thank you so much for joining in I think
we're in the midst of uh the festive
season uh wishing wishing you all a
great Happy Diwali to you and your
family members stay good stay fit stay
happy and uh uh we are excited in terms
of what quarter 3 untils for us and I
hope it wish it brings us all good luck
thank you so much and look forward to
interacting with you uh one to one as in
when your time permits thank you thank
you so much thanks thank
you thank you on behalf of ICI lombar
General Insurance Company Limited that
concludes this conference thank you all
for joining us you may now disconnect
your lines